

Josh Shone

Full-stack software developer

26.09.1989

Perlin

@ josh.shone@gmail.com

joshshone.com

\(+49 1765 793 7870

Hi, I'm Josh - a full-stack web and native applications developer living in Berlin (originally from Canberra, Australia). I have around 9 years experience, covering UX/UI design, native applications, low-level multimedia processing and modern HTML5/JS.

Employment

KIWI.KI GmbH

Full-stack developer

Berlin

2016 - 2018

2 years, 6 months

Developed and released an overhauled version of KIWI's web-based portal for housing companies, covering back-end work (Python, Flask), database refactoring (PostgreSQL), front-end design and implementation (ES6 Javascript, Backbone, Foundation CSS), build system re-tooling (NodeJS, Gulp), and deployment (Kubernetes).

My work at KIWI was often truely full-stack, with tasks requiring me to flash hardware to test new firmware, delve into dense SQL queries, all the way up to UI-design and user-experience considerations; even some graphic-design.

General Dynamics Mediaware

2012 - 2015 3 years, 4 months

Native application programmer

Web developer

P Canberra, Australia

Initial role as C++ programmer engaged in performance analysis, debugging and feature development on a large codebase. Worked in a mid-sized Agile team adhering to well-defined processes for issue-tracking, continuous integration, customer feedback and development iterations.

Helped develop the company's flagship product InStream, a high-performance multi-threaded video processing service for broadcast television. Also engaged in R&D, producing working prototypes for new products - one of which went on to be used by Australian firefighting services.

Took on a new role as primary web developer after showing initiative by producing performance analysis tooling with HTML5. Went on to develop a company-wide framework for service control utilizing websocket-based RPC (WAMP) and reactor-based networking (Twisted). Was also responsible for UI design, mockups, user-testing and producing high-quality documentation.

NCH Software

■ UI Designer

Native application developer

3 years, 4 months

• Canberra. Australia

2009 - 2012

Was responsible for creating several native desktop applications from scratch, including a non-destructive photo editor and musical notation software. Initial concept, design, mockups, prototyping, development and release was handled either solo or in small teams. Highlights:

- · Designed a unique modeless editing UI for sheet music.
- · Implemented a dynamic level-of-detail system for smoothly scaling fast fourier transform visualizations.
- Developed a high-performance non-destructive image transformation and layering system.

Education

Academy of Interactive Entertainment

ন্ত্ৰ Adv. Diploma of Professional Game Development

Cert IV in 3D Animation for Games and Film

Covered a broad range of computer science and visual design topics, including:

- Realtime games programming in C++ (Visual Studio)
- Composition, layout and prototyping
- 3D content creation and animation (3dsMax)
- Use of realtime graphics engines (Unreal)

Deutsch Akademie für Sprachen

Ongoing

2007 - 2008

P Canberra, Australia

P Berlin

ক্র A2 level German

I have decided to take a break from full-time software development and am currently taking advantage of a language-learning visa to learn German which will help with my goal of acheiving permanent residency.

Skills

HTML

Over 5 years professional experience with modern web standards, client-side rendering, responsive design etc. Some topics delved into, both professionally and personally:

- · WebRTC/Websockets
- · Advanced Canvas and SVG based animation
- · Various SPA techniques and use of Service Workers

Node.js

Node and its build tooling and package ecosystem has been a mainstay for many projects and products I've worked on.

Python

Gained a deep knowledge after using Python professionally for many years in server-side networking. I have experience developing, maintaining and deploying Python-based APIs and applications.

C++

Long and deeply involved history with C++ professionally, in personal projects and while studying games programming. Strong OOP design, multi-threaded/high-performance disciplines, advanced use of language features.

Gc

I am familiar with Go and use it in personal projects. I'm looking forward to using it professionally.

Linux

Linux has been my preferred development environment for most of my career, and I greatly value the speed and simplicity of an installation that I have personally customized.

Javascript

Experience with developing large, well structured JS codebases, with ES6/ES7 language features and an emphasis on writing clean, functional-style code.

My coding style and priorities when writing Javascript come from a background in statically-typed languages, which I feel helps me write testable and reliable codebases.

CSS

I extract a perverse pleasure from debugging puzzling layout glitches and implementing designs that thoroughly cover every edge-case.

I have experience with pre-processors like SASS and LESS, and both developing styling with modern CSS3 and highly cross-browser compatible stylesheets.

Kubernetes

I have experience working in an entirely Kubernetes-based development pipeline, where I have helped deploy and manage pre-production and staging environments.

SOL

I have experience writing SQL-backed server code and applications with async/non-blocking and high-performance queries. I've been responsible for large-scale database refactoring, performance analysis and customer data anonymization.

Git

Used extensively both professionally and personally. Have a solid understanding of underlying concepts, and use it for the swiss-army-knife toolkit it is.

Web frameworks

Foundation, Backbone, Bootstrap, KnockoutJS